hairlossrevolution.com 2019-07-16

# Privacy Policy - Hairguard

**Who are we?**

Hairguard is the organisation which collects personal data from [www.hairguard.com](https://www.hairguard.com/), in turn making it in to a data controller. Hairguard uses the data in order to improve the site experience , provide users with relevant content, and also service contracts such as the delivery of orders. This is in an effort to help sufferers of hair loss on their journey to regrowing their hair naturally.

**1 Who’s in control?**

Hairguard is the “controller” of all the personal data collected and used from this site. This in turn means that is is our responsibility to decide how and why individuals’ data are used and ensuring that they are handled legally and safely.

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted directly here: gus@hairguard.com

Please use the subject ‘Data Protection:’

**2 What data do we collect and where from?**

Data is collected from various points on the site, and during the checkout process. Typically, the first is when a visitor signs up for our newsletter (which may include a free PDF, guide, or eBook).The data collected at this point is solely the email address of the visitor.

If a user goes on to place an order on the site through the checkout then we will collect the following data:

  * Full name
  * Email address
  * Full billing address
  * Shipping address (if different to billing address)
  * IP address
  * Timestamp of the order
  * Phone number (if it is chosen to be provided)

We do not process or control any data classed in any of the special categories. 

**3 What do we use your data for?**

  * We will use your data to service order contracts, ensure that orders are delivered to the correct address
  * We will use your data to help manage any queries you may have
  * We may use your data to profile our aggregated customer demographics
  * If you have opted in to receive marketing emails then we will use your data to provide you with the content.

**4 How do we use your data?**

Hairguard will process (collect, store and use) the information provided in a manner that is compliant with the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). It is our objective to keep your information accurate and up to date, but for no longer than is necessary. By law we are required to retain information, such as that which is required for income tax and audit purposes. How long the personal data should be kept may also be governed by specific business-sector requirements and agreed practices. Personal data may be held in addition to these periods depending on the business needs.

**5 What is our legal basis for using your data?**

In most cases you will have opted in to receive free content, giving us your consent to process your data in order to deliver that content to you. If you have placed an order with us then we will use your details to service the contract of your order. This primarily includes ensuring that the contents of your order are delivered to the address specified. We will also retain your data for legal purposes such as audit and accounting.

**6 Freedom of information**

Under the Freedom of Information Act 2000 we are required to provide certain information in response to Freedom of Information requests. You can make a request by emailing info@hairguard.com. In order to respond to requests we will need to collect your email address.

**7 Who do we share your data with?**

We share your personal data with some third parties in some circumstances, as required by our business processes. This includes the use of third party suppliers to perform various services for us. The third party suppliers we share your personal data with are as follows: 

  * A third-party fulfilment company which handles orders for us 
  * A third-party email marketing provider
  * Third-party payment processing providers
  * A third party data tracking and management provider

**8 How long do we keep your data for?**

Hairguard will process and hold personal data for at least six months, unless you withdraw your consent in which case we will delete your data. We require at least six months in order to be able to uphold our 180 day guarantee for purchases. We may hold your data for a number of years for legal reasons, primarily accounting purposes.

**9 What rights do you have?**

At any point while we are in possession of or processing your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights:

  * Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you.
  * Right of rectification – you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
  * Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply to have a right to restrict the processing.
  * Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you transferred to another organisation.
  * Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing.
  * Right to object to automated processing, including profiling – you also have the right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling.
  * Right to judicial review: in the event that Hairguard refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined in Section 11 below.

**10 How can you contact us?**

If you have any queries or concerns about this Privacy Policy and/or our processing of your personal data, please feel free to get in touch with our Data Protection Officer via dataprotection@hairguard.com

**11 What if you have a complaint?**

If you have a complaint please first get in contact with us so that we may resolve it for you. If you are still not happy then you have a right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Officer (ICO). You can find out more about this by visiting [www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)

**12 What if this policy changes?**

From time to time we may make changes to this Privacy Policy. When we do we will update this page to reflect the changes. For significant modifications we will notify you by email.

**Consent**

By giving your consent to this Privacy Policy you are giving us permission to process your personal data specifically for the purposes identified earlier.

Hairguard requires consent in order to process your data. You may withdraw consent at any time by writing to [dataprotection@hairguard.com](mailto:dataprotection@hairguard.com).

**The Use of Cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

**Links to other websites**

This site could contain links to other websites that are relevant. Once you have clicked on a link to leave our site, please be aware that we don’t have nay control over those other websites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Medical Disclaimer

The content on this site is provided as an information resource only, and is not to be relied upon or used for any treatment or diagnostic purposes. The content does not amount to medical advice and should not be treated as such.

Always seek the advice of your physician or other qualified health provider before implementing anything you read about on Hairguard.com, or with any questions you may have regarding a medical condition. Never disregard professional medical advice or delay in seeking it because of something you have read on this website.

If you think you may have a medical condition or emergency, call your doctor, go to the emergency department, or call emergency services immediately. Reliance on any information provided on this website or from employees is solely at your own risk.

The statements on this website and the associated products have not been evaluated by the FDA and are not intended to treat or cure any disease. 

### Liability

This website, the content and the products on the site are provided “as is”. To the fullest extent permissible pursuant to applicable law, Hairguard disclaims all warranties, express or implied, and shall have no liability, for any damages, loss, injury, or liability whatsoever suffered as a result of reliance on the information contained in this site.

Links to educational content not created by Hairguard are followed at your own risk. Hairguard is not responsible for the claims of external sources.

### Typographical Errors

Whilst every endeavour has been made to ensure the typographical accuracy of the content on this website, Hairguard is not liable for your actions, and the loss or injury that may occur, as a result of the content written on this site.

Hairguard does not warrant that:

  * the information on www.hairguard.com will be always available, or available at all
  * the information on www.hairguard.com is complete, factually correct, accurate, up-to-date, or non-misleading.

### Interactive features

Hairguard provides interactive features on this website that allow users to communicate with us.

By using the website and it’s features you acknowledge that any communication you receive will likely be incomplete and may even be misleading due to the short and limited nature of communication through the site’s features.

Any communication you may have using any the site’s interactive features does not constitute specific advice and therefore should not be relied upon.

## Earnings Disclaimer

Any profit made from the sale of products on this website is re-invested, primarily back into this website and the associated products in order to create the best possible resource and product line for men and women who suffer from hair loss. Our aim is to help those who are going through this horrible condition to the fullest extent. 

Your support in visiting this website and purchasing these products enables us to expand and improve our offering, empowering people all over the world to combat their hair loss naturally. 

From time to time, we may link to content or products outside of this website. While we do not earn commission on this links, these linked sites are only for your convenience and therefore you access them at your own risk.

This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish.Accept [Read More](https://www.hairguard.com/privacy-policy/)
